Oh no!
噢，不！
I just don't understand what's happening!
我就没明白发生了什么？
Poor Travers!
可怜的 Travers ！
Silence!
安静！
Father!
父亲！
- No, no! No!  - But I must..
- 不，不    - 但我必须
No, Anne! Don't go near him.
不，Anne，别靠近他
I... am... the Intelligence!
我...是...大智慧！
- ANNE: No. No
- He can't be.
- 不, 不    - 不可能是他
Listen to me! I speak to you with this man's voice /11.7
听我说！我通过这个人的声音同你们说话
because the time has come for you to understand my purpose.
因为现在是时候让你们了解我的目的了
What's he getting at?
他得到了什么? fixme
Quiet!
安静！
What do you want?
你想要什么？
You defeated me in Tibet, Doctor.
你在西藏打败了我，博士
Yes.
是的
Now you have fallen into the trap that I have so carefully prepared for you.
现在你落入我的圈套了，如此精心地为你准备的圈套
What do you want?
你想要什么？
You! Your mind will be invaluable to me. Therefore I have invented a machine /47.7
要你！你的大脑对我来说将是无价的。因此我造了一架机器
that will drain all past knowledge and experience from your mind.
可以从你的大脑抽取你过去所有的知识和经验
But you'll kill him!
那会杀死他的！
Oh, no. He will survive, his mind unharmed - only empty
噢，不会。他会活下来，大脑也不会受损，只是空了
You can't - we'll fight!
你不能 - 我们会反抗！
That will not do. The Doctor must submit willingly.
那没有用。博士必须自愿服从
And if I... if I do submit, what of the others?
如果...如果我服从，其他人会怎样？
Then the others will go free.
那其他人可以走
And my father too?
我父亲也可以吗？
Oh, him too. I'm only using his body to communicate with you.
哦，他也会。我只是用他的躯体同你们交流
He didn't help you before, then?
他以前没帮助过你吧？
Oh, no. I have many other human hands at my command.
哦没有。我还有其他不少人听我使唤
And who are they?
他们都是谁？
Always questioning! Even now, you're seeking to destroy me! /58.8
这么多问题！即使到现在，你也还在寻求毁灭我的方法！
I see I shall have to guide your thoughts.
我看我必须引导一下你们的思想了
No, Jamie, no!
不, Jamie, 不要！
Cooperate and the child will be unharmed.
You have twenty minutes to make up your mind.
合作的话这孩子就没事．你有二十分钟时间做决定
Let me go, Doctor!
放开我, 博士！
Jamie, don't be a fool! You don't stand a chance.
Jamie, 不要犯傻！你一点机会都没有
Let me go! Victoria!
放开我！Victoria!
Let me past, Colonel!
让我过去, 上校！
No. The Doctor's right. There've been enough lives wasted.
不, 博士是对的．已经有太多性命被浪费了
Please... my wrist... Professor!
求你了...我的手腕...教授！
Eh! Wait a minute!
呃！等一下！
What is it, Evans, what's the matter now?
什么事, Evans, 现在什么情况？
Stand back everyone!
每个人都往后退！
I thought I heard it go!
我觉得我听到它走了！
Yes, well we'd better make sure. Evans - you, myself
and McCrimmon will go and search the place./?
是, 但我们最好要确认清楚．Evans, 你, 我和 McCrimmon 去搜一下这个地方
Doctor, you'd better stay behind here and get on with your tinkering.
博士, 你最好待在这里, 继续你的破解工作
Professor, please, you're hurting me! My wrist! Professor!
教授, 求你了, 你弄疼我了！我的手腕！教授！
Yes... yes, that should complete the circuit, good... I wonder...
是的... 是, 这样这个电路就完成了, 很好... 我在想...
There's only one way to find out.
只有一个方法可以弄明白
Yes. Certainly no sound out there.
是的．但这里没有声音fixme
Shall we chance it, then?
我们赌一下, 怎样？
Why not?
为什么不呢？
Now!
动手fixme!
No! Back! No!
不, 回来, 不！
Push! Push! Push, hard as you can!
Push, get your back to it! Get your back to it!
前进, 前进, 有多快走多快！回去, 回去！
Fire door - by the stairs - go and unhitch it,
and I'll try to hold this. Go on, McCrimmon!
fixme
You sure?
你确定吗
Yes, go on! Go on!
是的, 继续, 继续！
Alright, Colonel, come on!
好了, 上校, 快点！
Strange, it's not picking up. The Intelligence
must be transmitting... I wonder why it's not working...
很奇怪, 没有信号．大智慧一定在传输... 很奇怪它为什么不工作...
Aha! Success! It's going, Anne! Come along.
啊！成功了！它可以走了, Anne！快过来
Oh, oh that's marvellous. I'm sorry I'm being so long
- this is such a fiddling job.
哦, 这太棒了．很抱歉用了这么长时间 - 还真有点费神
Help you in a minute...
自己玩一会儿吧
There we are. Now then...
差不多啦, 现在应该...
Yes, you see, it's homing!
对了, 你看, 它在归巢！
There we are...
再来看看...
Do we go on or turn back?
我们是继续呢还是掉头？
Let's go on.
我们继续
Right.
好
Come on, what are you waiting for?
快点, 你在等什么呢？
Hey, wait a minute!
嘿, 等一下！
This is Victoria's! We're on the right track!
这是 Victoria 的！我们走对了
No, don't shoot!
不, 别开枪！
Is that thing on our side, then?
那东西是我们这边的, 这么说？
It is now. Stop!
现在是了．停下！
Were you scared?
你害怕吗？
Eh? Oh no, no, I mean, I just got up here to get a better aim, that's all./?
呃？哦不, 不怕．我是说, 我只是上来好瞄准, 仅此而已
How did you make it stop then?
你怎么让它停下来呢？
Simple - I told it to.
简单 - 我告诉它停就停
Here - ball. Why don't you go back where you come from?
给你 - 球, 你为什么不回到你来的地方？
Now, pull the other one.
现在, 拿出那一个
Oh, show him, Doctor.
哦, 给他看看, 博士
Alright, I will. Move forward.
好, 我会的．前进
Stop... Move to the left... Stop.
停... 向左移动... 停
There you are, how about that?
给你了, 感觉怎么样？
Hey, that's great! Make a smashing toy, that would.
嘿, 太棒了！这可变成一个强力玩具了fixme
Toy? That's a highly complex piece of equipment.
玩具？那可是一个高度复杂的设备
Oh, is it? Well I don't see how it's going to help us.
哦, 是吗？但我看不出来它怎么能帮我们
But it obeys our commands!
它会服从我们的命令！
So?
怎样？
Well, once we get it inside a Yeti, we'll have a powerful ally!
这样, 一旦我们把它装到一个雪怪体内, 我们就有了一个有力的同盟！
Inside a Yeti?
装进雪怪体内？
Yes, certainly. Will you help us?
是的, 当然是．你能帮我们一下吗？
You must be joking, Go near one of them things?
I may be stupid, but I'm not daft...
开什么玩笑, 走到那帮东西旁边去？我可能是笨点, 但我不是傻子
Oh very well, Anne, I shall have to do it myself.
哦, 好吧, Anne, 我就自己来干
Oh, I'm coming with you, Doctor.
哦, 我跟你一起去, 博士
No no, it's far too dangerous.
不不, 这太危险了
There you are, what'd I tell you?
看吧, 我怎么说的？
Not another word, I'm coming with you.
啥也别说了, 我跟你去
Hold it.
拿着它
Staff Arnold? It can't be, we'd given you up for lost!
Staff Arnold？不可能啊, 我们都认定你已经消失了！
Easy, easy...
放松, 放松...
That's it.
好了
Sorry about this, sir.
很抱歉, 头儿
What happened?
发生了什么？
I don't know. Can't remember.
I were pushing the trolley through the fungus, and... /07.0
我不知道, 想不起来了． 我把推车推过了那道网, 然后...
and I blacked out. I thought I were... falling./?
我晕过去了．我觉得我在...往下掉
When I come to, sir, I were in the tunnels... /17.3
当我醒来的时候, 头儿, 我在隧道里...
Where's the Doctor, sir? I met the Professor and the girl back there...
博士在哪儿, 头儿？我在那里遇到了教授和那个女孩儿
Victoria! Is she alright?
Victoria! 她没事吧
Yeti - guarding them, but... I promised I'd tell the Doctor, sir.
雪怪在看着他们, 但...我答应过我要告诉博士, 头儿
Right. Come on, back to HQ.
好, 来吧, 先回总部
I'm going for Victoria.
我要去找 Victoria
Really, we'd stand a better chance if we stick together.
Go ahead! Come on, Staff.
真的, 我们待在一起的话机会大写．走吧．来, Staff  fixme
Doctor's twenty minutes' almost up.
博士的二十分钟快到了
Evans, come out from behind that board.
Evans, 从那块板子后面出来
Oh, it's you, sir.
噢, 是你啊, 头儿
Where's the Doctor?
博士在哪儿？
Evans!
B-b-but y-y-y-you...
但是...你你你...
Stop bleating like a Welsh baa-lamb,
Evans, and answer the Colonel.
别像头威尔士羊羔一样咩咩咩．Evans, 回答上校的话
Sir?
头儿？
Doctor and Miss Travers, where are they?
博士和 Travers 小姐, 他们在哪儿？
Gone, sir.
走了, 头儿
Gone - where?
走了？哪儿？
Warren Street, I think.
Warren 街, 好像是
Why?
为什么？
After a Yeti, they said.
去找一个雪怪, 他们说过
Have a look at the board, sir.
看一下监控板, 头儿
Warren Street.
Warren 街
Come on!
快点！
No, not you, Staff. Evans, make yourself useful.
Get a dressing for the Staff Sergeant's head.
不, 不是你, Staff．Evans 你来吧, fixme
Yes, sir.
遵命, 长官
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你, 头儿
We're trapped!
我们被包围了！
Give me the control box, Anne.
把那个控制盒给我, Anne
The control box...
控制盒...
Yes.
是的
Haven't you got it, Doctor?
不是你拿着的吗, 博士？
What! What... hold the sphere!
什么！什么...拿着这个球！
Oh Doctor, you must have it!
哦博士, 肯定在你那里
Yes...
是的...
Doctor!
博士
Don't worry, it'll work!... It's got to work!
别担心, 能起作用的！...必须能起作用！
I know you said it only worked at short range, but for a moment...
我记得你说过它只在很短的距离内有用, 而且时间还不长...fixme
Well, don't tell me you were worried?
Would you like to hold this for me?
哦, 你是想说你不放心？你能帮我拿着这个吗？
It's alright, it's quite safe.
没事的, 非常安全
Nearly out... there.
Right.
是的
Now then - turn round!
现在 - 转身！
Oh, it works! You've done it!
哦, 有效！你成功了！
We've done it, you mean! Now then,
with my reprogrammed sphere and your control box, /33.1
是我们成功了！现在, 有了我改造的球体, 和你的控制盒
we should be able to work him over quite a distance.
And put your arm down!
我们可以长距离控制他．放下手来！
Now we've got a chance, Anne. Come on!
现在我们有点胜算了, Anne．快来！
Oh, mustn't forget him. Come on, Fred, at the double!
Staff! Staff!
What is it?
什么事？
What is it, Evans?
什么事, Evans？
Go on, Evans lad, get out of it!